[Music]
welcome to busy cental lunch event 2024
release Wave 1 today we will talk what
is new in our module E documents and
before we start first let's introduce
ourselves so my colleague hello I am
Manos and I am a software engineer at
business Central and today I have with
me yeah my name is Alexander toic and
I'm product manager and both of us we
work on this nice amazing functionality
about the documents and now this is the
second wave so we want to show what is
really new here agenda for today is
actually this is really short uh we will
first remind you what we deliver
previous wave some overview after that
we'll be Focus what is new briefly but
the most important is to show you full
demo end to endend scenario so you can
see in in the practice what is really
new okay um before we start with all
these new things I want to remind you
may we decided last wave to start with
um e documents uh module we were
thinking if we will start as a part of
Bas app or not and our decision was no
we will go with a new app so we deliver
e doent core app but if you can see this
light blue in a Bas app yes some part of
e doents are still in the B app and this
is because we didn't want to make some
breaking changes for existing U
electronic document Solutions because we
have many of partner based localizations
in some non microsof supported countries
that we already have uh introduced
invoicing so we didn't want to make all
these breaking changes so we adapted
what was necessary in a Bas app but our
f focus our main focus was on um e doent
core
app uh we try to put what is really
common in this app but then on the front
on the front on top of that app we made
another app for connection with third
party um access points service providers
together with this app we we cannot say
100% sure but in general we are looking
to have more than 80% of all features
you will need in documents after that
some small things adaptions are still
related with uh specific localizations
maybe something is missing here and we
are listening your feedback so if we
need to improve something and we know
that we need to improve some things to
add some new features and we are doing
this and yes this is what we are talking
today about that uh but let's look this
is uh basic framework common and plus
integration with external Services what
you expected and what Microsoft is doing
on top of that we already deliver some
localizations and we are planning to
deliver more localization on top of that
as a independent local uh apps and we
expect this from Partners as well from
you to make your own localizations and
not only
localizations sometimes you want to
extend Microsoft localization for
example in Denmark or Belgium whenever
we have and you can add some specific
industry U industry Solutions on top of
that maybe some additional documents or
even if you look in these third party
access points if you are uh isv if you
are provider you can enable some
additional documents maybe you will
enable quotes or orders exchange all
these documents so we are good with that
we have good framework and we deliver uh
the basic functionality about invoices
but now you can build more if you
need uh I don't want to explain all
these details what we have um in our
solution uh about all corter models how
we support in general we can support two
coordinate three coordin four coordinate
models and let's imagine that four
coordinate model is the most complicated
one and I just want to remind you not
about how exchange uh how we exchange uh
documents but how we exchanging messages
because this is important and this is
especially important when we talk about
this um uh third partyy access providers
so we are exchanging different type of
messages through them and in
general let's imagine now we are sender
we are seller and we have our internal
messaging system inside the busy Central
we assume something similar exists in a
receiver RP or if our receiver is busy
Central user we are pretty sure it
exists there we know we made it so in in
uh inside the business Central we have
internal messages system but then this
messages system communicate with uh
access points with third party services
and now in some cases uh we are
connected with defit third party access
uh points because as a payo or some
other rule in some situations government
uh governments do not allow us to
connect directly with their services in
some countries this is possible so we
cannot say all the time when we can
directly connect or not but in general
in almost all these situation we have
communication with some services so now
we have communication in in both
directions when receiver get uh document
they need to approve or reject so
they're sending this uh message to
receiver access points in the time our
um bus Central as a seller we
communicate all the time with our access
point listening and expecting some new
message to get and if receiver
approve this message will be exchanged
between receiver access point and our
access point that means cender access
point and we will listening we will
collect this information and get it back
to busy Central this is important
understanding how all this messaging are
functional so this is important part
this is not only sending anding
documents messaging is important we need
to know if our customer receive rejected
or some other status
document so now I will go further what
is new I will briefly explain what is
new because my colleague magos will
explain much more in details in the Demo
First what we deliver we deliver P
format support why because of your
feedback when we created first framework
we didn't support any format so you uh
you were expected to build your own
format you want to use and and based on
your feedback we conclude this is not
the best design not Design This is the
not the best user experience because
you um needed something to test it so
now we decided let's bring P B3 because
this is the most used format globally
and we went one step further we say if
you want to deliver this let's make in
both of types we can communicate
different types of formats so you can
see uh good Role Models so you can
decide what is better for you we deliver
this as a code so pure code you have in
a code how to communicate in PayPal how
to create actually payp uh documents how
to use it but we also added data
exchange definition so if you choose
data exchange definition you will get
additional fasta where you need to map
uh all your incoming and incoming and
delivering documents purchas documents
with a specific definitions then we have
the next thing is about connection I
mentioned all these messages with
external access points but now what is
about we created this app uh as a
connect of with third party Services
there is uh authentication model
communication model as I already uh show
messaging model so all of these things
are inside this app currently we are
supporting only one access point but we
are planning to add more access points
there and completing functionality is
extendable so you can easily build your
own app and we will talk a little bit
more on the end about how how to extend
how to build your own app to use uh this
functionality uh for your services
especially this is some local service
you can easily extend it uh what is
important more uh not this this is only
that is possible to extend uh you can
easily um connect uh with a setup with
uh choosing everything there or you can
pre-configure when you run service you
can automatically get all information so
you just need to enter your credit itial
and it will work and of course as we are
using third party access points for the
moment then you choose from
non-integration to this one current
integration or eventually tomorrow more
integration you will get consent this is
required because you are moving outside
of busy
Central what else we deliver some
localizations and this is not where we
stop in this moment we deliver
localization for Denmark both formas obl
and P so you can choose both of them um
in Danish um uh environment when you go
to uh document types you can choose
payal document exchange and obl in
Belgium we deliver payal format so this
is currently uh fully compliant with
Danish and Belgium uh requirements and
regulations but now we are planning
additional localizations I cannot say
exactly when uh it depends of
enforcement from country to country but
minimum what we are planning in next two
week
um we have uh planed German localization
Spanish localization and Australian New
Zealand localization as well actually
for Australia New Zealand uh we are
using PayPal but this is not B3 so we
need to adapt PayPal format for
Australia New Zealand and this is
something what we are planning to do but
even more we already have um from
previous um uh times we have some Legacy
e documents in voice hisory documents in
Italy and Mexico so we are planning in
following period to upgrade Italian and
Mexican functionality to new e documents
so everything depends uh we will
challenge ourself and Depends uh how we
did a great job or not or we need to
improve something more but we want to
upgrade our existing function our
existing localization and to make new
localizations what else one big
feature uh we had an let's say small
issue with previous
one uh make making sales invoice sales
electronic invoice it was let's say easy
you create you post sales document we
have some uh let's say visard the
background we will create this in a
payal format we will send and let's say
this is easy not so bad not so
complicated but when it comes to
purchase process it becomes uh much more
complicated and what we can see more and
more countries enforcing uh electronic
invoicing they do not enforce
immediately to have from this year for
example sales uh invoice in electronic
but they are enforcing to receive
invoices so this purchase part was
extremely important for us in this first
relas we could create when you when you
get uh electronic document we could uh
create automation to automatically
create purchase invoices in busy Central
but we couldn't handle with purchase
orders and it was a problem if you are
working with a lot of inventory you want
to have already created purchase order
and now you need to match and it was a
problem problem we didn't have it
but now again based on your feedback it
was one of the most important things you
asked and we deliver this
functionality now with the new new
release you can match without any
problem actually what you can do if
there is um no purchase order in your
system and you decide you want to create
purchase order for this vendor system
will automatically create new purchase
order based on the same rules as for
purchase invoice it just depends how you
will set up your vendor but if for this
vendor there is some existing purchase
order system will map incoming
electronic documents with this existing
purchase order and matching will work
one to one one to many many to one so
you will see in demo how you can do
it um of course we build co-pilot on top
of that but all the time there are some
reasons uh if you cannot use copilot so
you still you you can use manually
matching so you are not blocked if if
you cannot use copilot for some reason
and I'm planning to finish my part of
presentation but before that I want to
emphasize one important thing ktoo demo
tool in the beginning we had uh some
just few modules there but we decided
let's bring more and more to uh to
partner and to customer to test it now
we deliver e documents demo data so we
have full module for e doents um uh with
e information what you have there we
have uh new items and pretty big uh big
number of items so you can make good
examples there and what is more this is
ready for completely ready for sales
process we already have configured
customers with the workflow so you can
just post uh sales invoice and you can
track how it look like in a sales
process in documents what is happening
with logs so and you will see uh from my
colleague in demo but this is already
ready for purchase prod process what you
have there already imported files you do
not need to make some uh PayPal files to
test it you will have already created
electron incoming electronic documents
with um imported files so you can easily
test manually matching or even even
matching with co-pilot so everything is
there what is important just to to know
before enable you need to have because
there dependency you need to uh first
enable comma module and Warehouse module
after that you need to enable e doent
module and everything will work
everything will be there so you can just
start and use
it and okay that was about what is new
briefly what is new now Magnus please
make it much better it's a great demo I
know you prepared thanks Alexander yeah
I got the the fun role of actually
demoing a lot of the the stuff that we
have for you I will start where
Alexander left us off with the the demo
data that we have for the eent framework
so to do so I will go to contoso demo
tool I will open it up and here we can
see the new e doent contoso module that
we have added for this release and this
module uh provides you as Alexander
briefly explained with some new items
that you can use as well as all the
setup that we need today for the demo
for both sales and purchase processes so
I'm going to go ahead and click generate
this shouldn't take very
long and while that's generating I can
also uh just briefly say that this will
also create a default e document service
that we're going to be using today so
really there is not a lot you have to to
set up if you want to test it out
yourself just go here generate the the
demo data and you should be uh getting
started very very
fast so with that done let's go to the E
doent
Services we have them here and we can
see that we now have a new new service
that we can use and I will just open it
up and we will take a
look here we can see that the the
document format that we are actually
providing in the framework is the pebble
format and this is something that is in
two types of solutions one of them is a
code solution which is based on pre
existing XML ports we had in the product
and we also decided to add a data
exchange version or data exchange
solution so to speak and this we will go
and and select and I'll show you how to
set it up so under the data exchange
definition uh we will now have to go and
actually set up uh what types of
documents we want to to use with the
data exchange and today I'm doing two
things I'm doing a a sales process and
I'm doing a purchase process and to do
so I need to define a sales invoice and
for that sales invoice I need to go
under the export data exchange
definition and I need to select sales
invoice export here and this is one of
the formats that we provide for you out
of the box for free super cool and then
we can also go and create for purchase
process a purchase enice will just
selected and then for the import data
exchange definition I'll have to go and
select the format that is called E doent
P invoice import and that's essentially
all you need to configure for for
getting this to work with the data
exchange one thing you do need to to
know and need to do is also to go to
supported document Types on the document
service here and here you need to select
those types of do ments that should work
together with this service you can see
we are already pre-filled for sales and
services so I'm just going to go ahead
and also add purchase invoice and
purchase credit
memo like this and that's essentially
everything you need to to get started
trying this out yourself one thing I
will note and as Alexander also briefly
mentioned before today we don't have a a
service integration you can see it's set
to no integration normally when you have
a a service in a production environment
you would have set up some kind of uh
service integration implementation here
to an and external uh third party but uh
today we won't send or receive any
documents we already have those from
from generating the demo data so that's
super nice you don't need to deal with
that all that I will now do the sales uh
process and to start that I will go to
one of our customers because one thing I
do need to do is I need to make sure
that on this customer we have a document
sending profile uh selected that has
eents enabled and of course in the demo
data we are also providing this for you
so you can just use the eents document
sending
profile that's it now we can go and
create a sales
invoice and uh because we're using pble
I I need to fill in a reference number
for today's demo I'm just going to use 1
2 3 4 it doesn't really matter but
normally you would actually have a
reference to an order here if if you
need that and then I'm going to select a
desk and I'm going to just put one in
quantity here and that's essentially
everything I need I'm just going to post
the invoice that should be rather
fast let's see yes and uh now we can go
to the posted invoice and what happened
in in the background because the
framework is actually running in
background jobs and what we are
providing with the demo data is that we
have actually added a a workflow that is
enabled um that is connected to the E
doent service that we are also providing
and basically we will subscribe to the
posting routine and whenever you post a
supported document type for uh for this
service we will pick it up and run this
workflow execute the workflow and
essentially that will then export the
the sales invoice in the format that you
select selected um had you had a a
service integration at the end it would
also have uh send it off uh to that so
if we go to the related Tab and click
under e doents open E
doent we will now have a e doent that we
can inspect here we can see under the
document field that it is pointing to
the sales invoice it is processed we can
even see what workflow was executed
with as well as the service status right
so here we have the E documents service
that we we are using today and we can
see that the status of this is exported
if we look under the locks here we have
only a single lock today this is that it
was exported but every step of the way
would be be locked so that you can
easily audit what is going on with a e
doent um we can also see that it
actually has a file size and this allows
you to when there is a file size you can
go under the export file action and
actually download uh the output and
inspect it if you want to so I will not
do that but I will close this one and uh
just briefly mentioned that if we had a
service integration uh it would also
contain a log that would say that it was
sent somewhere or it was pending to be
sent or um depending on on how you have
your
implementation and that's it all of this
happened in the background the user that
is uh that's posting the invoice doesn't
have to go and look at this uh as set it
happens in a background uh job but now
we showed you where you can find it if
you're
interested then we're going to shift
gears a little bit I'm going to jump
back to the RO Center and we're going to
look at a purchase process which is
where we actually invested a lot of the
time uh this wave with what Alexander
mentioned matching e doent lines to
purchase orders that's a really cool
process uh so so we will look at that
one and one thing that we added uh on
the role Center is these new Q cards
under the E doent
activities here you can see that we have
uh one of them called matched uh
purchase orders and this is essentially
purchase orders in the system where we
have received an e document from outside
received it into the system and we
managed to find that that there is a
link to one of your existing purchase
orders and we automatically link it and
then we make you aware here that this
now there is an action for you to go and
actually match the E doent lines to the
purchase order lines so I'll click these
and uh and we can then see we have these
six and this is all generated by our
fantastic demo data uh so you don't need
to set a lot of stuff up you can just go
directly and try out this scenario um
from the RO
Center and as you can see uh we have
this uh this action called map e
document in the top um which I will
click in a second but before I do so uh
for this environment I'm on I haven't
enabled our co-pilot features if you're
interested in uh the new co-pilot stuff
we're doing I think personally it's very
cool I would definitely recommend you to
watch another session we have called e
invoicing with
co-pilot um it is like uh super
interesting to see this process I'm
about to do manually can be done with a
simple click almost it saves you a lot
of time and something we're very excited
to ship
um so definitely go check out that
session it's uh it's worth it after of
course you watch the rest of this so uh
I'll go and and click map e document
will open up the matching page and now
I'll just briefly explain what you're
seeing here um if you have seen bank
reconciliation matching before this is
built around the same concept so it
should be pretty familiar to you if not
uh on the left we have our e doent lines
this is what we have read in from from
file um and on the right we have our
purchase order lines and the task for
the user in this sense is to match
everything that is on the left to
something that is on the right such that
you can go and update the purchase order
and do either full or partial invoice uh
so let's take a look um we can see on
the E doent imported lines here that we
have a field quantity and we have a
field matched quantity right so our task
is to actually have a a match quantity
that is equal to quantity um so it's a
very cool stuff you can multi select
three or more if you want I know that
these first three lines line 10,000
20,000 and 30,000 are all something that
is related to the Precision grind home
um of course I prepared the demo so I
will click these two and then I will go
under the matching action here and click
uh match
manually and this will then highlight
them um a green color means that it's a
it's a complete match uh we can see that
the available quantity was 15 meaning
there was 15 we could assign to we've
now assigned 10 because the quantity to
invoice is updated to 10 we can also see
that match quantity on the left here is
uh the same as quantity and we can even
go and click this to inspect in more
detail what the match is uh so let's try
that we see that we have a match between
line 30 ,000 to 10 10,000 we are showing
you what the two descriptions are
because sometimes the descriptions are
not similar this is something that the
copal really strong helping us with if
we have items that are not exactly the
same but similar we can also see that we
have a a match quantity and as well what
is the cost of the E document or what
was the cost on the eent line and what
was the cost on the purchase order line
sometimes in in this case they are the
same sometimes they can be different and
that is okay we do allow you for you to
do a matching where the cost is not uh
exactly the same we will notify you just
to make sure that that is actually what
you want and if you go ahead and apply
to purchase order we will then update
the the purchase order lines with that
cost you received such that you can
invoice
correctly so I'll close this um and I'll
just quickly mention as Alexander also
said we we allow for a a many to one
that I Illustrated here selecting three
matching to one you can also do a many
uh or one to many let's say where you
select multiple purchase order lines and
and only match to a single uh e doent
line but the last one here I am just
going to match uh the luxury grinder to
Smart grind home uh and this is a one to
one symbol and now everything on the
left is green that is good that means
that we have matched all of them and the
final thing for me to do is uh simply to
to go to home and click apply to
purchase order as I said this will then
update the purchase order lines to give
them um the correct cost as well as
discount um it will also update the
quantity to invoice and the final thing
we will do is that we will update the
the vendor invoice number let's see that
go to here you can see that the vendor
invoice number is now updated with the
document number as well as the document
date has also been updated to reflect
what was on the
document and that's it that's
essentially the PO the purchase process
in a nutshell um you could go ahead and
and post it I won't do that now I'll
will hand it back to my colleague
Alexander who will tell us a little bit
more about if you want to extend and
build on top of our framework y great
demo Magus thank you and as you can see
a really big automation even if you're
doing manually you just need to connect
there and system will automatically
collect all this information from
incoming document to uh do vendor
document number they update all lines
this is this is still big automation
even if you're are doing manually and
this is the most important not only big
automation this is not no now this is
not even blocker so now you can use
everything as a standard is used earlier
in busy Central together with e
documents okay instead of uh wrapping up
um we would like to extend this topic
for a few minutes because this is
important uh we want to show you and we
want to encourage you to extend this
function ality maybe some additional
features even we will continue to invest
adding some additional features there
but much more probably much more
important making localization especially
in partner based uh localization
countries so the most of our supporting
countries uh have partner-based
localization so make your localization
on top the solution this is much better
than anything else you used earlier uh
making even if you have some electronic
invoicing inside this is much better
using this framework there are much more
more automation so you can just add
format connection to service and it will
work and um this is one part another
part is if
you uh access uh access point service
provider if you're P provider or a local
service provider build your own app for
a connector to your services and it will
be easy used for all other
partners so uh you can see this link and
there is documentation how to extend
this document functionality when you go
there you will find that we have
document format interface for create and
receive documents you can understand
this is in in one or another Direction
what is happening in documents then we
have integration interface for sending
receiving messaging this is what we
already talked about and there are some
set of e doent hel helper code units so
you can find a lot of interesting
information a lot of important
information there of course all the time
we we can say we can improve it and give
us the feedback and we will try to
improve documentation to make it much
better for you and now uh I will again I
will give a word for my colle Magnus to
explain in a few minutes little bit more
technically what we have there and how
you can use these interfaces yeah I
think we should also mention that if you
build your own extension on top you get
the co-pilot feature as well natively it
will work so that's super cool let's uh
recap a little bit of the process that I
showed you for for both sales and vice
versa process uh purchase so essentially
we have a BC document that we need to to
send to some Authority endpoint uh
usually and we created the E documents
such that you take a business Central
document you use an an export um format
to create this into a electronic
document version and then we have our
service integration um or integration
implementation that then decides how we
send this out to Authority endpoint and
vice versa when we receive something
again we're using the integration
implementation to actually get the data
from a a provider into a electronic
document and then we use a import
document format to translate that back
into a a business Central
document what the framework provides out
of the box for export and import is that
you can also uh do these field mappings
so say that you before you export or
before you import you want to translate
some uh some values you can do so uh in
under the service you can specify this
as a setting and Define it yourself um
as we saw when I did the post the sales
invoice everything is running in
background job so it's not disturbing
it's not requiring anything from from
those people that are are invoicing or
working with the documents on a
day-to-day basis everything is running
smoothly in the
background then we also make sure that
we lock everything and again this is
because that you can all audit what is
happening with the E document so there
is a trail so you can see exactly uh
what is the current state of a specific
electronic document we also allow you to
set up a retention policies so that you
can actually decide for how long you
want to store Data before we clean it up
because some of these tables can get
quite big and that's maybe not in the
best interest uh for
you finally we also do uh error handling
for you in the framework um should there
be a runtime error in the Al code then
we will catch it um and uh basically um
if you want to allow or tell the users
about um some error that you you want to
throw or want to uh yeah do you can
basically um use our helper code units
to uh yeah to lock errors uh that will
then be presented on the E doent page
finally we have a dashboard and that you
saw before I used it the Q cards where
you can then gauge
what is the the current status of the of
the E documents are there any that you
need to take action on for instance do
we have any new purchase orders that are
are matched right this is all something
that we provide uh what we ask of you if
you're interested in building uh on top
of this uh the things I just mentioned
they are here in in blue then we have
our two interfaces both for import
export that's one interface where you
define how specifically you want to to
read data out of BC and back into as
well as how you want to communicate uh
that is the integration implementation
that you will make so that is the the
core framework and then of course the
localization like the Danish one that we
also shipped uh we actually just
Implement these two
interfaces um and and that's it it's a
very straightforward simple thing to do
one thing that we also allow you to do
is to uh build a setup with it sometimes
there are some administrative setups
that you need to do for a service you
can then uh add this on top to to make
it easier for for the users that you're
building the extension
for and with that I will uh hand it back
to you Alexander to close out the
session thank you Magnus as you can see
uh we have definitely great
documentation and great idea how to
extend it and of course if you again if
you find something is missing please
contact us we are more than open to help
all Partners to build their own apps and
to extend the
functionality and now uh we just want to
call you to watch some other
presentations as Magnus already
mentioned we have introducing to e
invoicing matching with co-pilot great
session uh this part about matching what
magot is playing but this time with
copilot fully automated a really useful
usage of co-piloting great examples and
additional one is if you are coming from
Denmark uh we updated um uh new session
with Danish bookkeeping Act features
because there are some new things in the
meantime happened from uh previous pre
previous uh wave so we want to be clear
about that even if you had the office
hour we want to give more information
about uh new Danish bookkeeping act and
now please use our Yammer AK msbc Yammer
we have our channels there different
channels we are open for communication
for feedback whatever you want to
communicate directly with product group
then we are open communication fitter or
X um please join our office hours every
month we have good uh office hours and
use BC BC ideas akms BC ideas we are
really we are we are looking every time
every time when you publish when you put
some idea some of program managers we
are getting this ideas in our devop so
we know what you're asking we are
tracking uh we are looking to to deliver
this we cannot deliver everything of
course but we looking to deliver as more
as possible and we are looking on your
feedback on your ideas on votes and so
on and if you cannot remember all these
URLs please do not forget this one akms
BC all so going there you can find not
only these four links but much more
dozens of different links with a very
important and interesting resources
about busy Cal and yeah we can say this
is everything for uh what we plan for
this session uh we can say thank you but
we hope we will see you on live Q&A one
week after this Louch event so we will
be open both Magnus and I we will be
there and you can ask everything in life
face to face we will
talk so use this opportunity once more
thank you thank
you